# **CV**

Mads Hvelplund Grækenlandsvej 129 2300 København S, Danmark

Mobile: 50550272

E-mail: <a href="mailto:mhvelplund@gmail.com">mhvelplund@gmail.com</a>
LinkedIn: <a href="mailto:http://bit.ly/li\_mhvelplund">http://bit.ly/li\_mhvelplund</a>

Stack Overflow: <a href="http://bit.ly/so\_mhvelplund">http://bit.ly/so\_mhvelplund</a>



# Introduction

I like the craft of software development, especially the process of understanding a complex business domain and reducing its problems to manageable chunks. My experience includes designing everything from individual features to complete platforms in domains from waste management to payment processing.

I have a strong background in Java, but I also have a good grasp of the .NET family of languages, and many modern JS frameworks.

On a personal level, I'm an extrovert and I get along well with people. I also enjoy learning from others and teaching them what I know.

# Education

1995-2006: M.Sc. In Computer Science from DIKU, Copenhagen University

# Industry experience

Financial (online payment), 4 yrs. Government (health), 2 yrs. Medical, 1 yrs. Waste Management, 1 yrs.

# Work- and project experience

Ekstern Konsulent, Netcompany A/S (jan 2018 – mar 2018)

FLIS (Fælleskommunalt Ledelsesinformationssystem)

Rolle: Developer

# Beskrivelse:

I worked with Netcompany on FLIS, a government platform for exchanging performance data between municipal leaders. My work dealt mostly with testing and optimizing in-house tools to achieve faster and more stable execution.

Erfaring: C#, SSIS, SQL Server

# .NET department manager, Theilgaard Mortensen (May 2015 – December 2017)

#### .NET department manager

Role: Manager

#### **Description:**

I managed the .NET department, consisting of 3 consultants. My team delivered both ad hoc development at hourly rates and an in house developed electronic patient journal system used by the Danish Government.

As manager, my main focus was on improving the quality of deliveries on our EPJ product. I introduced code reviews and mandatory unit testing, and worked with support to standardize integration testing prior to releases.

Experience: Code review, Continuous Integration, Integration Testing, Unit Testing

# Electronic patient journal system (EPJ)

Role: Architect, Team lead

#### **Description:**

I served as team lead and architect for the team that maintained TM's EPJ systems for child dental care, post-natal healthcare, and the Copenhagen dentist school. The child dental care system alone had more than half of the Danish municipalities with every child in them as customers. The back-end was Java based and the front-end was a C# WinForms application.

Experience: C#, EPJ, GEPJ, Java, VB.NET, Web services, WinForms

## Self-service modules for EPJ system

Role: Systems Developer, Web Developer

#### **Description:**

I was the lead developer on the implementation of self-service modules for the EPJ system that integrated with NemLog-In.

**Experience:** Angular2, ASP.NET MVC, Bootstrap, C#, HTML5, Web services, OIOSAML.NET, SAML, SSO

#### Waste management portal

Role: Consultant, Systems Developer, Team Lead, Web Developer

#### **Description:**

I maintained waste management self-service portals for ISS and Novo Nordisk.

Experience: ASP.NET MVC, C#, HTML5, jQuery, MS Reporting Services, Web services

## Quality control

Role: Architect, DevOps

#### **Description:**

I developed and introduced Docker/DropWizard middleware to ensure that only tested code would make it into the main product branches, and to link auto generated change logs with the issue tracking system.

Experience: CruiseControl.NET, Java, Jenkins, Docker, Drop Wizard, Target Process, Web services

#### Architectural review

Role: Architect, Systems Developer

# **Description:**

I served as the main architect for most department projects, and I performed overhauls of the Java based back-end server's architecture, to replace homemade components with stock components from the Open Source community. The process helped reduce maintenance costs.

Experience: Bitronix JTA, Guava, Java, JAX-RS, Lombok, Web services

# Log and server monitoring

Role: Architect, DevOps

# **Description:**

I prototyped log- and server monitoring of our client solutions.

Experience: Docker, GrayLog, Nagios, NSClient, NXLog

# Systems developer, Endomondo (January 2015 – April 2015)

#### Endomondo application back-end

Role: Systems Developer, Web Developer

## **Description:**

I worked on the back-end used by the fitness app and the website during the transition from an Apache Wicket application to an OSGi/AngularJS solution deployed in AWS.

Experience: AngularJS, Apache Wicket, AWS, Java, OSGi, Web services

#### Unit testing

Role: Systems Developer

#### **Description:**

I rewrote the older parts of the backend to support unit testing.

Experience: JUnit, Mockito

# Architect, DIBS (July 2010 – December 2014)

#### **New Payment Gateway**

Role: Architect, Team Lead, Systems Developer

#### **Description:**

I designed and prototyped a platform built around horizontally scalable servers deployed in Amazon's AWS cloud. The system used event sourcing and the CQRS pattern to share the load of processing payments, while simultaneously feeding a business back-end.

The final system was based on Axon CQRS and Redis, but during development both ActiveMQ and Riak where in play.

Experience: Apache ActiveMQ, Axon CQRS, AWS, MySQL, Redis, Riak, Spring, Web services

# Server throttling Role: Architect

#### **Description:**

I designed, and helped implement, a configurable rate limiting proxy to during a hectic Christmas when the servers were buckling under the load. The system was conceived, developed and deployed over 48 hours, and was still in use 2 years later when I left.

Experience: Node.js, Redis, Web services

Systems developer, Eniro (March 2008 – June 2010)

## Support tool

Role: Systems developer

#### **Description:**

I took responsibility for the in-house front-end used by the customer service department, streamlined the build process, and rewrote the application to use dynamic model binding.

**Experience:** Java, Java Webstart, Swing, Web services

#### Data integration

Role: Systems developer

# **Description:**

I worked on the core data exchange collecting data from multiple sources and exporting them to the head office, providing data for both the websites and the print division.

Experience: Batch Processing, Java, J2EE 1.5, Web services

## B2B master data portals

Role: Systems developer, Web developer

#### **Description:**

I worked on several portal sites for B2B projects for the Swedish head office.

Experience: Java, jQuery, Freemarker, OAuth 1.0, Spring, Web services

# Consultant, Theilgaard Mortensen (March 2006 – February 2008)

# Lotus Notes integration

**Role:** Systems developer, Web developer

# **Description:**

I designed and developed an integration layer that allowed data from an external data warehouse for Business Denmark.

**Experience:** J2EE 1.5, Web services

Bogportalen and Gyldendals Bogklubber **Role:** Systems developer, Web developer

# **Description:**

I developed e-commerce sites for a number of major Danish companies including Gyldendal.

**Experience:** J2EE 1.4, WebSphere Commerce, Web services

# Work experience matrix

# Level description:

- 1. I've worked with this, but I'm rusty
- 2. I can maintain existing solutions
- 3. I can work confidently from scratch or existing code
- 4. I can teach others
- 5. The subject is a core competence

| Areas                     | Years | Last | Level |
|---------------------------|-------|------|-------|
| Architecture              | 6     | 2017 | 4     |
| Back-end                  | 11    | 2017 | 5     |
| Consulting                | 4     | 2017 | 3     |
| DevOps                    | 2     | 2017 | 3     |
| E-Commerce                | 2     | 2008 | 2     |
| Frontend                  | 7     | 2017 | 4     |
| Government                | 2     | 2017 | 3     |
| Open Source               | 11    | 2017 | 4     |
| Payments (finance)        | 4     | 2014 | 3     |
| Requirement Specification | 6     | 2017 | 4     |
| SOA                       | 11    | 2017 | 5     |
| System Design             | 6     | 2017 | 4     |
| System Development        | 11    | 2017 | 4     |
| System Integration        | 11    | 2017 | 5     |
| Team Lead                 | 6     | 2017 | 4     |
| Waste Management          | 1     | 2017 | 2     |
| Web Development           | 7     | 2017 | 4     |
| Web Services              | 11    | 2017 | 5     |
| Technologies              | Years | Last | Level |
| .NET                      | 2     | 2017 | 3     |
| Ajax                      | 7     | 2017 | 2     |
| Amazon Web Services (AWS) | 5     | 2016 | 3     |
| Angular 2                 | 2     | 2017 | 2     |
| Apache ActiveMQ           | 2     | 2012 | 1     |
| ASP.NET                   | 2     | 2017 | 3     |
| ASP.NET MVC               | 2     | 2017 | 3     |
| Bootstrap                 | 2     | 2014 | 1     |
| C# (C-Sharp)              | 3     | 2018 | 3     |
| Continuous Integration    | 7     | 2017 | 4     |
| CruiseControl.NET         | 2     | 2017 | 5     |
| Docker                    | 4     | 2017 | 4     |
| EPJ                       | 2     | 2017 | 3     |

| Technologies (cont.)   | Years | Last | Level |
|------------------------|-------|------|-------|
| FreeMarker             | 3     | 2012 | 2     |
| HTML5                  | 7     | 2017 | 3     |
| IBM WebSphere Commerce | 2     | 2008 | 1     |
| Integration testing    | 7     | 2017 | 4     |
| J2EE                   | 4     | 2010 | 3     |
| Java                   | 11    | 2017 | 5     |
| Java Swing             | 2     | 2010 | 3     |
| JavaScript             | 7     | 2017 | 2     |
| JAX-RS                 | 2     | 2017 | 4     |
| JAXB                   | 4     | 2014 | 4     |
| JBoss                  | 3     | 2010 | 3     |
| Jenkins                | 6     | 2017 | 4     |
| jQuery                 | 4     | 2014 | 2     |
| JSON                   | 6     | 2017 | 5     |
| LINQ                   | 2     | 2017 | 2     |
| Linux                  | 16    | 2017 | 3     |
| Microsoft IIS          | 2     | 2017 | 3     |
| Microsoft SQL Server   | 2     | 2018 | 3     |
| MySQL                  | 5     | 2015 | 4     |
| Nagios                 | 2     | 2017 | 3     |
| Node.js                | 1     | 2012 | 2     |
| Pull Requests          | 7     | 2017 | 5     |
| Redis (database)       | 3     | 2014 | 3     |
| REST                   | 6     | 2017 | 5     |
| Riak                   | 2     | 2013 | 1     |
| SAML                   | 2     | 2017 | 4     |
| Single sign-on (SSO)   | 2     | 2017 | 3     |
| SOAP                   | 10    | 2017 | 5     |
| SoapUI                 | 2     | 2014 | 4     |
| Spring                 | 5     | 2014 | 4     |
| SQL                    | 11    | 2018 | 4     |
| Swagger                | 2     | 2017 | 5     |
| Tomcat                 | 11    | 2017 | 4     |
| Unit Test              | 8     | 2017 | 5     |
| VB.NET                 | 2     | 2017 | 1     |
| Web                    | 11    | 2017 | 4     |
| Web Services           | 11    | 2017 | 5     |
| WinForms               | 2     | 2017 | 2     |
| WSDL                   | 10    | 2017 | 5     |
|                        |       |      |       |